# UGWUODO CHIOMA

Experienced Front End Developer with 2+ years of experience in React. Excellent reputation for resolving problems and improving customer satisfaction. Organized and dependable candidate successful at managing multiple priorities with a positive attitude. Willingness to take on added responsibilities to meet team goals. Hardworking and passionate job seeker with strong organizational skills eager to secure entry-level Front End Developer position. Ready to help the team achieve company goals.

10/12 Bishop Onyeabor GRA Enugu, Nigeria

(234) 907 624 2114 sheila.codes.m@gmail.com

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# ALX Africa, Nairobi, Kenya — FrontEnd Engineer Intern

FEBRUARY 2022 - OCTOBER 2022

- Proved successful working within tight deadlines and a fast-paced atmosphere.
- Collaborated with team members to achieve target results.
- Developed and maintained courteous and effective working relationships.
- Exceeded goals through effective task prioritization and great work ethic.
- Worked to maintain an outstanding attendance record.
- Created plans and communicated deadlines to complete projects on time.

# **Freelance**, **Enugu** — *FrontEnd Developer*

JANUARY 2020 - PRESENT

- Collaborated with stakeholders during development processes to confirm creative proposals and design best practices.
- Worked cooperatively with client services, sales and design team in a deadline-driven environment.
- Tested web-based product functionality and delivered iterations to customers.
- Produced websites compatible with multiple browsers.
- Performed user experience quality assurance testing to identify and remedy shortcomings.
- Designed and updated layouts to meet usability and performance requirements.
- Guided customers on project stages and iterations with input on best practices, user needs and technology capabilities.
- Advocated for well-tested and documented, high quality code.
- Coded using HTML, CSS and JavaScript to develop features for both mobile and desktop platforms.

## **SKILLS**

- HTML/CSS
- React
- Git
- Software Best Practices
- Figma
- Bootstrap
- Jira
- CI/CD
- SRS
- Code Debugging
- MS-Word
- Writing Skills

#### **LINKS**

**GITHUB:** 

https://github.com/Sheila-a

**MEDIUM:** 

https://medium.com/@ugwuodo20

**EMAIL:** 

ugwuodo20@gmail.com

LINKEDIN:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/chio

ma-ugwuodo-940900217

PORTFOLIO:

https://chioma-ugwuodo.netlify.app

### **EDUCATION**

## **University of Nigeria**, **Nsukka** Nigeria — *B.Agric*

SEPTEMBER 2016 - NOVEMBER 2022

- Member of National Association of Agricultural Students
- Elected Financial Secretary for 2016/2017 Class in 2017

#### **LANGUAGES**

English, Igbo, Spanish